A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Books FA952
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Books
1955-1981
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA952
1 Cubic Feet
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Separated Materials
ALL BOOKS REMOVED TO RAC LIBRARY 8/9/1988.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
One copy of each book published by The Rockefeller University Press is deposited in the Rockefeller University Archives by the Press. See card catalog for complete publishing information on each.
Arrangement
Arranged in chronological order and by author.
Conditions Governing Access
All books are open for scholarly research.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 549
Science -- Study and teaching; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Medical technology; Medical research; Life sciences; Biology -- Research; Medical education; Medicine, Preventive; Medical sciences; Rockefeller University; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Bolin, Bert, ed., The atmosphere and the sea in motion, 1959
  Separated Materials
  Removed to RAC Library, 8/9/88.
- Hill, A.V., The ethical dilemma of science and other writings, 1960
- Dubos, René, The unseen world, 1962; (2 copies, to be used for reprinting only)
- Corner, George W., History of The Rockefeller Institute, 1901-1953, 1964
- The Scientific endeavor, Centennial celebration of the National Academy of Sciences, 1965
- Jones, Harry W., ed., Law and the social role of science, 1966
- Glass, David C., ed., Neurophysiology and emotion (Biology and behavior, 1), 1967
- Quarton, G.C., Melnechuk, T., Schmitt, F.O., ed., Neurosciences; a study program, 1967
- Cranefield, Paul F., ed., Paired pulse stimulation of the heart, 1968
- Glass, David C., ed., Environmental influence (Biology and behavior, 3), 1968
- Glass, David C., ed., Genetics (Biology and behavior, 2), 1968
- Morehouse, Ward, ed., Science and the human condition in India and Pakistan, 1968
- Woodford, F. Peter, ed., Scientific writing for graduate students, 1968; paperback; hard cover 2 copies
- Pfaffmann, Carl, ed., Olfaction and taste, 1969
- Schmitt, Francis O., ed., The neurosciences; second study program, 1970
- Kobler, John, The Rockefeller University Story, 1970
- Shannon, James A., ed., Science and the evolution of public policy, 1973
- Kone, E.H. and Jordan, H.J. eds, The greatest adventure; basic research that shapes our lives. Intro, by Isaac Asimov, 1974
- Griffin, Donald R., The question of animal awareness, 1976
- Dubos, René J., The professor, the Institute and DNA, 1976
- Kobler, John, The Rockefeller University Story. 2nd edition, 1977; paperback, 2 copies
- Brinkley, B. R and Keith R. Porter, eds., International cell biology, 1976-1977
- Chargaff, Erwin, Heraclitean fire; sketches from a life before nature, 1978
- Griffin, Donald R., The Question of Animal Awareness: Evolutionary Continuity of Mental Experience. Revised and enlarged edition, 1981